## **Emmaculate Wamboi**

Nairobi, Kenya • +254712589930 • emmaculatewamboi@gmail.com • <u>linkedin.com/in/emmaculate</u> • <u>https://ewamboi.github.io/Portfolio/</u>

### **Summary**

As an experienced data analyst, technical skills were leveraged to achieve measurable objectives and drive organizational growth. Accurate election outcomes were ensured, operational efficiency was improved by 15%, and strong teaching and mentoring skills were demonstrated.

As a customer support agent, improved overall customer experience by 25% and successfully mitigated customer complaints. As a data intern, maximized my skills, resulting in a 40% increase in productivity and reduced error rate.

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

SasaKazi • Nairobi, Kenya • Internship • Feb 2023 - Apr 2023

### **Digital Marketing intern**

- · Assist in keyword research and optimization to improve organic search rankings
- Optimize website content, meta tags, and URLs for better visibility.
- Perform research on industry trends, target audience preferences, and competitor activities

# Independent Electoral and Boundaries Commission • Nairobi, Kenya • Part-time • Jul 2022 - Aug 2022 Deputy Presiding Officer

- Delivered reliable and credible election results by ensuring 100% accuracy in the counting and tallying of votes.
- Maintained a perfect record in the safe storage and safeguarding of all entrusted election documents, materials, and equipment.
- Improved the election process by 15% through effective oversight and management.

### CCI KENYA • Nairobi, Kenya • Part-time • Apr 2021 - Feb 2022

#### **Customer Support Agent**

- Provided prompt customer service by answering 50+ inbound and outbound calls and 100+ emails per day within 30 seconds.
- Increased customer satisfaction by 25% through fostering positive customer interactions, engaging them in conversation, and demonstrating empathy.
- Resolved customers' issues on the first contact, delivering successful resolutions and ensuring satisfaction through prompt and accurate communication.

### CSV Research Solutions • Part-time • Aug 2021 - Jan 2022

#### Data Intern

- Developed a comprehensive client-based database, leading to a 25% improvement in customer satisfaction and a 20% increase in repeat business.
- Managed a team of 10 individuals, resulting in an increase in productivity and a 15% decrease in errors.
- Generated weekly and monthly reports to keep management informed on key performance metrics, leading to 30% of improvement in decision-making processes.

### Kenya National Bureau of Statistics • Nairobi, Kenya • Part-time • Nov 2019 - Feb 2020

### **Research Assistant**

- Administered research questionnaires in-person to 200 participants over a 3-month period with an 85% response rate.
- Gathered additional data for validation purposes by following up with 95% of respondents.
- Submitted daily reports to the supervisor with 100% accuracy and good timeliness.

### **Telkom Enterprise** • Part-time • Jun 2019 - Sep 2019

#### Sales Representative

- Coordinated a team of 8 sales representatives and contractors, boosting sales revenue by 15%.
- Monitored team performance against KPIs, identifying areas for improvement and implementing training programs that resulted in a 10% rise in conversion rates.
- Created and maintained a detailed work schedule and work plan increasing productivity threefold
- Presented weekly project updates to stakeholders, resulting in a 90% approval rate for project milestones.

### Safaricom Limited • Part-time • Aug 2018 - Apr 2019

### Sales Representative

- Offered product information and advice to 50+ customers daily, resulting in a 95% customer satisfaction rating.
- Directed the project of a building acquisition, completing all documentation accurately and within the required timeline.
- Guided 30+ customers per week on the payment procedure and informed them about new products.

#### **EDUCATION**

### **Bachelor of Science in Statistics and Programming in Statistics**

Machakos University • Machakos • Sep 2014 - Nov 2018

### **CERTIFICATIONS**

### Google Data analytics Certificate

Google • Feb 2021 - Jul 2021

### Nanodegree in Data Analytics

Udacity • Jul 2022 - Oct 2023

#### **SKILLS**

Managing projects efficiently, Providing exceptional customer service and support, Proficient in Microsoft Office Suite, R, Data Visualization using Tableau and PowerBi, Solving complex problems with creative solutions, Python, Data Mining and Data cleaning, Communicating effectively both verbally and in writing, SQL, SEO Awareness, Content Creation and Copywriting